Guide to the Oliver C. Winston Papers ca. 1930-1973
Winston, Oliver C. Papers ca. 1930-1973
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Oliver C. Winston Papers c. 1930-1973
4408
Oliver Winston
17 cubic ft.
Letters, photographs, clippings, printed materials, and ephemera.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Materials relating to Oliver C. Winston's work in Washington, D.C., Baltimore, Binghamton and Cornell University.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
City planner. Oliver C. Winston held a B.A. and B.S. in architecture from The Rice Institute. He worked for the Housing Division of the Public Works Administration in Washington from 1934 to 1938; was Regional Director of the United States Housing Authority in Washington, 1939-1947; was Executive Director of the Housing Authority of Baltimore City, Urban Renewal Coordinator for Baltimore City, and Director of Baltimore Urban Renewal and Housing Agency. He later served in planning positions in Binghamton, New York and at the Office of Regional Resources and Development at Cornell University. Winston died on April 25, 1992 at the age of 86.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Biographical material including photographs and early correspondence; Correspondence, appointments, notes, lectures, speeches, conferences and seminars relating to his work in Washington, D.C. as well as files relating to his work in Baltimore and Binghamton; and teaching and department files relating to his work at Cornell University.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Winston, Oliver C.; Cornell University.
Subjects:
City planning--United States.; City planning--Maryland--Baltimore.; City planning--New York (State)--Binghamton.; City planners.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Houston
Boxes 1-2
Material relating to Winston's private practice of architecture in Houston, Texas, 1927-1934. Chiefly correspondence and studies, plans, etc. for projects undertaken by his firm. Includes resumes and biographical information.
Series II. Washington
Boxes 2-4
Material pertaining to Winston's positions in Washington, D.C. as Project Planner for Housing, Division of Public Works Administration (1934-1938) and Regional Director of the United States Housing Authority (1939-1947)
Series III. Baltimore
Boxes 5-8
Covers Winston's positions as Executive Director of the Housing Authority of Baltimore City (1947-1959), Director of the Baltimore Urban Renewal and Housing Agency (1957-1959), and Urban Renewal Coordinator for Baltimore City (1955-1956). Primarily Correspondence speeches and printed materials
Series IV. Binghamton
Boxes 8-12
Material relating to Winston's position as Executive Director of the Valley Development Foundation, Inc. (1959-1966). Includes speeches correspondence and printed materials.
Series V. Cornell University
Boxes 13-23
Covers Winston's Career at Cornell as lecturer in the Department of City and Regional Planning (1959-1974) and Director of the Office of Regional Resources and Development (1965-1971). Consists chiefly of studies for urban renewal projects in various central New York communities and publications on planning by various institutions and individuals associated with Cornell. Includes lecture materials, student papers and correspondence.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Houston
  - Resumes & Biographical Information (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Family Information (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Personal Notes", 1932 - 1933 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Texas Rehabilitation & Relief Commission, June 1933 - January 1934 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, January 1932 - September 1933 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, October 1933 - December 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, January 1934 - May 1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, June 1934 - August 1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Millar's Housing Letter, January 1932 - April 1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Millar's Housing Letter, 1933, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Stayton Nunn, March 1934 - January 1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Nunn & Winston Contracts, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Nunn & Winston Stationery (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Bills & Receipts", April 1934 - November 1934 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Housing Law, 1933, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Housing Law Pamphlets (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Housing Study Bulletin, June, July, September 1934 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - National Association of Housing Officials (NAHO) - Organizational Meeting, November 1933 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - NAHO, 1933, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Negro Housing Project" (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Houston Housing Project", 1932 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Housing Survey for Houston, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Housing Surveys, miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Subsistence Homesteads", 1933 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Housing & City Planning Bibliography (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Winter Haven, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 9 - 10)
  - River Oaks, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 11 - 15)
- Series II. Washington D.C.
  - General Report: Syracuse Housing Authority, August 1937 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - The Niagara Frontier Plans for Peace, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Report on the Operations of the Chicago Housing Authority, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Federal Emergency Administration of Public Works - Housing Division history (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Outlines for Study of Projects", 1936 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Memorabilia - Jackson Day Dinner, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Memorabilia, FDR Inauguration (includes invitation and program), 1941 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Memorabilia - Puerto Rico (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Speeches, 1938 - 1944 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Articles (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - National Conference on Planning, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - NAHO annual meeting, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - NAHO organization handbook, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - National Conference on Family Life, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 12 - 13)
  - Austin Housing Project application, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - "Miscellaneous data" (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
  - History of Greenbelt (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence - Greenbelt towns, 1947, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, September 1937-May 1938 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, June 1938-September 1938 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, October 1938-December 1938 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, January 1939-February 1939 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, March 1939-April 1939 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, May 1939-June 1939 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, July 1939 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, February 1940-July 1940 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, January 1942-October 1942 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, January 1943-April 1943 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, May 1943-August 1943 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, September 1943-December 1943 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, January 1944-March 1944 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, April 1944-July 1944 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, August 1944-October 1944 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, January 1944-December 1944 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, January 1945-March 1945 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, April 1945-June 1945 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, July 1945-September 1945 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, October 1945-December 1945 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, January 1946-March 1946 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, April 1946-June 1946 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, July 1946-September 1946 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, October 1946-December 1946 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, January 1947-March 1947 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, April 1947-June 1947 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, July 1947, December 1947 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: Puerto Rico, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Puerto Rico, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - American Institute of Planners material, 1946, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1934-1942 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Series III. Baltimore
  - Baltimore positions-appointments, 1955, 1956, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Director's Office, 1956, January 1957-May 1957 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Director's Office, August 1957-December 1957 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Director's Office, January 1958-May 1958 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Director's Office, June 1958-August 1958 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Director's Office, September 1958-December 1958 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Personal, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, March, April 1959 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - NAHO column, 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - NAHO speech, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Speeches, December 1952-December 1955 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Speeches, March 1956 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Speeches, April 1956-October 1956 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Speeches, November 1956-December 1956 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Speeches, January 1957 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Speeches, February 1957-March 1957 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Speeches, April 1957-May 1957 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Speeches, June 1957-October 1957 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Speeches, November 1957 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Citizens Planning and Housing Association of Baltimore, 1941-1944 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Commission on Government Efficiency and Economy Publications, 1943, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Housing Authority of the City of Annapolis Annual Report, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Housing Authority of Baltimore City, State Law and Amendments (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Dear Sir- /Housing Authority of Baltimore City (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Tentative Master Transportation Plan /Planning Commission of Baltimore, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Everybody Plans /Planning Commission of Baltimore, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Urban Renewal in Baltimore /Planning Commission of Baltimore, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Civic Center Sites /Baltimore Department of Planning, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Report of the Urban Renewal Study Board, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Appendices to the Report of the Urban Renewal Study Board, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Reports to the Greater Baltimore Committee, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Progress Report 2 Greater Baltimore Committee, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Housing Code Enforcement Greater Baltimore Committee, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Final Report Baltimore Metropolitan Area Study Commission, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Research Study: Development of the George St. Site, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Report on Baltimore Urban Renewal & Housing Agency, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Report to Mayor J. Harold Grady, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Program Dimensions Baltimore Urban Renewal & Housing Agency (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Statement on Disposition Policies Baltimore Urban Renewal & Housing Agency, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets (Box 6, Folder 19-21)
  - Appointment, Director, Baltimore Housing Authority, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Study of Preparation of Applications Procedure Baltimore Urban Renewal & Housing Agency, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Urban Renewal Plan: Demonstration Project MD D-2 Baltimore Urban Renewal & Housing Agency (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Urban Renewal Plan: Project No. 3-C Baltimore Urban Renewal & Housing Agency, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Urban Renewal Plan: Project 4 Baltimore Urban Renewal & Housing Agency, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Urban Renewal Plan: Project 7 Baltimore Urban Renewal & Housing Agency, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Amendment No. 1 to Project No. 12 Baltimore Urban Renewal & Housing Agency, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Urban Renewal Plan: Harlem Park Project II Baltimore Urban Renewal & Housing Agency, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Review of Charles Center Proposal Baltimore Urban Renewal & Housing Agency, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Disposition Policy... Charles Center Baltimore Urban Renewal & Housing Agency, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Charles Center Urban Renewal Plan Baltimore Urban Renewal & Housing Agency (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Articles-Charles Center (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Pacific Coast Urban Renewal Clinic, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - International Seminar on Urban Renewal, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 14-15)
  - ACTION Southeast Urban Renewal Clinic, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1947-1957 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Award, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Regional Land Use Baltimore Regional Planning Council, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Industrial Land Development Baltimore Regional Planning Council, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Freeway Plan Baltimore Regional Planning Council, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Water Supply and Sewerage Baltimore Regional Planning Council, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Housing Market Analysis Baltimore Regional Planning Council, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Series IV. Binghamton
  - Appointment, Valley Development Foundation (VDF) Director (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Candidates for VDF Director (Box 8, Folder 7-10)
  - VDF Assistant Director recruitment, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Commissioner of Planning, Zoning, & Urban Renewal, recruitment, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - VDF Sr. Planner, Jr. Planner, recruitment, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - VDF Assistant Director, applicants, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 14-16)
  - Speeches, 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Speeches, 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Speeches, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - "Drafts-Letters and Articles Not Used", 1963 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Maurice Gold articles, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Foreign, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Donald Fleming, June 1965 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Albert Meyer, January 1966-March 1966 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - VDF and Broome County Charter Commission, December 1960-December 1963 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - VDF and industrial development, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: "The American City" Lectures, December 1964-December 1965 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Community Arts Council Conference, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - "Brazil trip", 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - "Ideas", 1963-1966 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - American Institute of Architects (AIA) Material, 1962-1964 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Community "Texture", 1962 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - FHA publications (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Citizens Committee on Neighborhood Appearance, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Hotel proposal, Nezelek, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Hotel proposal, North American Motel Corporation, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Hotel proposal, HRH and Treadway Inns, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Hotel proposals, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Proposed Binghamton Hilton, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Proposed 250-Room Hotel, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - "Hotel Meeting", 1966 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Downtown Project No. 1, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Downtown Project No. 1, Map (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Binghamton City Hall (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1963, 1964, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Hotel prospects, 1964, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "Hotel situation", 1964-1966 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - "Jane Jacobs book", 1962 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - "Architectural control" (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Binghamton Commission on Architecture and Urban Design, 1964, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Binghamton Commission on Architecture and Urban Design, Advertising sign control, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
  - Correspondence: August Heckscher letter, 1961-1965 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Martin Anderson book, December 1962-May 1965 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Material for article (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
  - International Federation for Housing and Planning, World Congress (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: "India paper" (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - "India paper" drafts (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - "National legislation", 1965 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - VDF statements, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - VDF reports, minutes, miscellaneous, 1966-1971 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Central Binghamton 1970, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Downtown Binghamton, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - The Economy of Broome County, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Broome County Urban Area Relocation Housing Survey VDF, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Non-Residential Relocation Survey; Downtown Renewal Project No. 1, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Market and Land Use Analysis: Downtown Renewal Project No. 1, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Binghamton Hotel-Motel Market, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Report on Traffic and Parking, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Industry Looks at the Hammer Report, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Residential Relocation Service, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Study of the Feasibility of Conversion to Office Space of Sisson's Department Store, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Market and Land Use Analysis: Downtown Project No. 2, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Downtown Binghamton: Urban Renewal Project 1, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Review of Project One Proposals, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Opportunities for Binghamton, New York, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Demonstration City Qualification Report, Binghamton, New York, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Binghamton Metropolitan Transportation Study, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Binghamton Governmental Center, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Application For a Grant of Funds, Binghamton, New York, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - The Binghamton Commission on Architecture and Urban Design, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Urban Design Project One, Binghamton, New York, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Downtown Core Work Force VDF, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous maps and plans (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Series V. Cornell University
  - Class Schedule, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Lectures, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Term Papers, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Student Roll, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Class Schedule, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Lectures, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Term Papers, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Student Roll, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Class Schedule, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Lectures, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Term Papers, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Student Roll, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Class Schedule, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Lectures, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Term Papers, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Student Roll, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Class Schedule, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Lectures, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Term Papers, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Student Roll, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Class Schedule, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Lectures, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Term Papers, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Student Roll, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Class Schedule, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Lectures, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Term Papers, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Student Roll, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Class Schedule, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Lectures, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Term Papers, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Student Roll, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Class Schedule, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Lectures, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Term Papers, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Student Roll, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Class Schedule, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Lectures, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Term Papers, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Student Roll, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Class Schedule, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Lectures, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Term Papers, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Student Roll, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Class Schedule, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Lectures, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Term Papers, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Student Roll, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Class Schedule, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Lectures, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Term Papers, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Student Roll, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Cornell University Guest Lectures, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Cornell University Guest Lectures, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Cornell University "Laidlaw seminars" (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Corning Community College lecture, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Rhode Island University seminar, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Dartmouth Lectures, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Seminar material (Box 14, Folder 23-26)
  - Student paper, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Student paper, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Student paper, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Student paper, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Student paper, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Student paper, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 2-8)
  - Student paper, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Cornell University, August 1959-December 1960 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Cornell University, January 1961-November 1962 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Cornell University, January 1963-December 1963 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Cornell University, January 1964-January 1966 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Cornell University and Ford Foundation Grant, 1967-1971 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Publications, 1962-1964, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: VDF, December 1966-June 1971 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Cornell University Retirement, June 1971 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Cornell University ORRD Final report, 1971, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: C.A. Doxiades, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Lyndon Johnson, 1963-1968 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Jimmy Carter, February 1977 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Congressmen, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1969-1971 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: AIA, 1970, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: National Association of Housing and Redevelopment Officials (NAHRO), 1970, 1971, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: Cosmos Club, May 1967-October 1974 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Speeches, 1966-1968 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Articles: Journal of Housing, December 1966 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Articles: "Urbanization Pattern for the United States", 1967 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Organization of Cornell Planners Conference, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Governor's Conference on Natural Beauty, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Conference on State Planning, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Dublin Conference, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - AIA Conference, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - NAHRO Committee on Review of NAHRO Programs & activities, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 9-11)
  - Metropolitan Area Studies (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Decentralization (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - National Growth Policy, 1973, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - ORRD Proposal, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Proposal to ORRD: "Industrialized Housing System", 1968 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Dept. of Urban Planning & Development, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 17-18)
  - Proposal to NYS Urban Development Corporation, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous reading lists, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Urban renewal agencies' organizational charts (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Awards (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Log of activities, 1960-1963 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Log of activities, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Log of activities, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Log of activities, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Log of activities, September 1965-January 1969 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Cornell University special Lectures, 1964-1965 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Tees-Side Survey, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Ithaca Scattered Site Housing Project (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - ORRD and Urban Development Center, 1970-1972 (Box 17, Folder 9-10)
  - OCW book, 1975-1978 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Ithaca 1990 Ithaca City Planning Board, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 12)